A Guide to the Henry Westfall Frye Papers, 1795-1935 (bulk 1830-1860)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Henry Westfall Frye Papers, 1795-1935 (bulk 1830-1860)
The Library of Virginia
45155
2.475 cubic feet (6 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Biographical Information
Henry Westfall Frye was born on 27 April 1804. He was the son of Henry Frye III (1762-1811) and Hannah Westfall (1776-1824). Frye lived in Wardensville, Hardy County, West Virginia, and was a justice of the peace for the county and treasurer of Capon Township. He was also a director of the Hardy and Winchester Turnpike Company. He married 1) Elizabeth Baker (1810-1832) on 15 September 1825 and 2) Mercy Moore (1809-1890) on 4 October 1834. Frye died on 6 February 1896 and is buried in the family cemetery in Intermont, West Virginia.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1795-1935, of Henry Westfall Frye (1804-1896) of Hardy County, West Virginia. The bulk of the collection covers the years 1830 to 1860. Includes accounts and receipts, correspondence, day book, estate papers of Ann Littler (ca. 1796-1855), records of the Hardy and Winchester Turnpike Company, papers of Benjamin Moore (1768-1849), promissory notes, and tax records.
The majority of the collection consists of summonses (warrants), 1838-1852, signed by Frye in his capacity as justice of the peace for Hardy County. The summonses concern debts of less than twenty dollars, and most of them are accompanied by the account, note, order, or fee bill that was in dispute. They are arranged by year.
Contents List
- Account Books (portions). (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Accounts and Receipts. (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- Accounts and Receipts (Frye). (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Accounts and Receipts (Frye) (Oversize). (Box Personal Papers Oversize Box 105)
- Anatomy and Chemistry Notebook. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Astronomy Lecture (portion). (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Attachment Bonds. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Attachment Writs. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bible Classes List. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Book - Holy Scriptures Extracts in Latin, 1849. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Broadside - Property of John Kinsey of Dauphin County (Oversize), 1845. (Box Personal Papers Oversize Box 105)
- Correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Day Book. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Deeds. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Delivery Bonds. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Deposition - Lee, Charles C. (Webster vs. Sager), 1847. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Diary Entries, 1825. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Estate of Ann Littler. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Evangelical Lutheran Synod of Virginia - Annual Minutes, 15-20 August 1872. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Fee Bills. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Fieri Facias (Fifas). (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Hardy and Winchester Turnpike Company. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Hardy and Winchester Turnpike Company - Broadside. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Hardy and Winchester Turnpike Company - Road Hands Accounts. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Hardy and Winchester Turnpike Company - Tolls Collected. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Hardy and Winchester Turnpike Company - Tolls Collected (Oversize). (Box Personal Papers Oversize Box 105)
- Horses, Mules, Wagons, etc Appraisement, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Indemnity Bond. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Journal of the House of Delegates (portion), 1801. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Moore, Benjamin. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Orders for Payment or Goods. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Orders for Payment or Goods (Frye). (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Parker's Percussion and Reaction Water-Wheel. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Promissory Notes. (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
- Scire Facias. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Senseney Bills. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Subpoenas. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Subscription List - Rev. Isaac Baker. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1838. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1839. (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1840. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1841. (Box 2, Folder 15-17)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1842. (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1842. (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1843. (Box 3, Folder 3-7)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1844. (Box 3, Folder 8-11)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1845. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1846. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1847. (Box 4, Folder 3-6)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1848. (Box 4, Folder 7-10)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1849. (Box 4, Folder 11-13)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1849. (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1850. (Box 5, Folder 4-8)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1851. (Box 5, Folder 9-12)
- Summonses (Warrants), 1852. (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- Tax Collected (Capon Township), 1868-1869. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Tax Tickets and Receipts. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Tax Tickets and Receipts (Frye). (Box 6, Folder 5)
- "The Teacher's Catalogue for West Virginia Schools, 1927-1928. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Tintypes. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Warrant Docket, 1843. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Wrappers. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Wrappers (Oversize). (Box Personal Papers Oversize Box 105)